<RECORD ID="661">
<TEXT>
<HOSPITAL>HLGMC</HOSPITAL>
<ID>2743471</ID>
Report Status :
SPECIAL PROCEDURES AND OPERATIONS :
<DATE>3-27-93</DATE> , cardiac catheterization and coronary and left ventricular angiography ; <DATE>4-2-93</DATE> , exercise tolerance test with Thallium .
Vasotec 5 mg PO b.i.d. , Isordil 10 mg PO q.i.d. , Ticlopidine 50 mg PO b.i.d. , Metoprolol 50 mg PO b.i.d. , Ciprofloxacin 500 mg PO q12h x seven days , nitroglycerin 0.3 mg sublingually prn chest pain .
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
The patient is a 73 year old female who was transferred for cardiac catheterization after ventricular fibrillation arrest in the setting of an acute inferior myocardial infarction and a urinary tract infection .
The patient was admitted on <DATE>3-16-93</DATE> to <HOSPITAL>Diy Hospital</HOSPITAL> for an E. coli urinary tract infection .
The patient was readmitted on <DATE>3-20-93</DATE> because of fever , chills and a sudden onset of ventricular fibrillation arrest , successfully cardioverted back to rapid atrial fibrillation and finally to sinus rhythm , where an electrocardiogram then showed ST elevation in inferior leads .
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION :
Her chest demonstrated bibasilar crackles .
the jugular venous pressure was seven centimeters , carotid upstroke normal .
no calf tenderness or peripheral edema .
HOSPITAL COURSE :
Review of these angiograms demonstrated a dominant right coronary artery with a focal 50% stenosis in the mid-portion .
The patient was maintained on heparin anticoagulation .
The patient had no further angina .
This showed no diagnostic electrocardiogram changes for ischemia and no angina pectoris .
The thallium images showed a large region of persistently reduced blood flow involving the apex and inferoposterior segments of the left ventricular wall .
This was consistent with scar .
In view of these findings , it was elected to discharge her on her present medical program .
<DOCTOR>CHPO E. JESCOBEA</DOCTOR> , M.D.
TR :
DD :
<DATE>06-13-93</DATE>
Dr. <DOCTOR>Ko Kollciem</DOCTOR> , <HOSPITAL>Retchard Healthcare</HOSPITAL> to Dr. <DOCTOR>Wall</DOCTOR>
</TEXT>
</RECORD>