<RECORD ID="796">
<TEXT>
<ID>693519617</ID>
<HOSPITAL>PUOMC</HOSPITAL>
<ID>2328487</ID>
<ID>769151</ID>
<ID>388371</ID>
<DATE>12/16/1997</DATE> 12:00:00 AM
END-STAGE RENAL DISEASE .
Unsigned
Report Status :
Unsigned
<PATIENT>LESS , LIESEANALE</PATIENT>
ADMISSION DATE :
<DATE>12/16/97</DATE>
DISCHARGE DATE :
<DATE>01/16/98</DATE>
End-stage renal disease .
ASSOCIATED DIAGNOSIS :
1. Right nephrectomy .
2. Cadaveric renal transplant .
6. Hypertension .
8. Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease .
11. Abdominal abscesses .
13. Respiratory failure .
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
The patient was a 53-year-old male with a longstanding history of renal disease with multiple complications and problems related to vascular access and hypercoagulable state .
These culminated in an attempted cadaveric kidney transplant undertaken on <DATE>12/16/97</DATE> , which was complicated by thrombosis and necrosis of the cadaveric renal vein within 24 hours .
The patient &apos;s course was subsequently characterized by recurrent pneumonias , possibly due to aspiration , and by hemodynamic instability .
He was transferred to the Medical Intensive Care Unit from the Transplant Service for ventilatory management in the setting of hypotension .
The patient was found to have substantial auto PEEP with an elevated dead space .
The patient had undergone two abdominal procedures following explantation .
The physiology at the time of transfer to the Medical Intensive Care Unit was consistent with a septic process .
CT scan demonstrated retroperitoneal collection containing both free air and extravasated contrast material .
The patient remained unstable .
He was taken to fluoroscopy , where oral contrast was demonstrated to be extravasating through a posterior duodenum .
There was no evidence of cardiac tamponade or specific underlying coronary dysfunction .
His course was complicated by atrial fibrillation requiring cardioversion .
Dr. <DOCTOR>Cantsleddjesc</DOCTOR> felt that no surgical approach to this problem or further intervention or radiologic procedures would be helpful .
TR :
TD :
cc :
<DOCTOR>LE FREIERM , JR</DOCTOR> , M.D. <DOCTOR>KIVERL NA CANTSLEDDJESC</DOCTOR> , M.D. <DOCTOR>I LYNIN STERPSKOLK</DOCTOR> , M.D. <DOCTOR>ETI CHAELKA MULKEVI</DOCTOR> , M.D.
cc :
Dr. <DOCTOR>Less</DOCTOR>
</TEXT>
</RECORD>