
<RECORD ID="824">
<TEXT>
<ID>839084838</ID>
<HOSPITAL>PUOMC</HOSPITAL>
<ID>7201663</ID>
Unsigned
Unsigned
3) Clostridium difficile colitis with diarrhea .
PRINCIPAL PROCEDURES :
On <DATE>3/27/95</DATE> , <DATE>3/28/95</DATE> , <DATE>3/30/95</DATE> , <DATE>3/31/95</DATE> , and <DATE>04/04/95</DATE> there were revisions and contrast injections to the biliary catheter drainage system .
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
The present illness is marked by presentation with jaundice and pain in <DATE>August of 1994</DATE> , and a computerized tomography scan that showed bile duct dilatation .
Since that time he had been persistently jaundiced and fatigued , until three weeks prior to admission when the patient had a biliary tube check , which showed things to be patent despite his rising bilirubin .
His lungs were clear .
His head and neck showed marked scleral icterus and a cardiac examination showed a systolic ejection murmur .
The abdomen was soft and had well healed right upper quadrant scar .
LABORATORY DATA :
He was admitted and started on intravenous antibiotics and studied with an abdominal computerized tomography scan .
What then ensued was multiple attempts to insure adequate biliary decompression by use of percutaneous transhepatic cholangiogram and placement of biliary catheters and stents .
The procedures took place on several days throughout the hospital stay with the sentinel pro cedure taking place on <DATE>3/28/95</DATE> , and this was placement of the 10 mm diameter metal wallstents .
Subsequent to that , he was found to have a subhepatic fluid collection , which was suspicious for a bile leak and therefore a drain was placed percutaneously into this collection .
On <DATE>3/31/95</DATE> and <DATE>04/04/95</DATE> , very mild revisions were made of these and the feeling was that solution had been reached with good drainage .
His bilirubin by the time of discharge had fallen from a peak of 28 down to a discharge value of 8 .
During the course of the hospitalization , he was found to have diarrhea and stool was sent and found to be positive for Clostridium difficile toxin and this initiated treatment with Flagyl 500 mg PO t.i.d. for two weeks .
On <DATE>04/04/95</DATE> , it was deemed he was ready for discharge and Dr. <DOCTOR>Blinjesc</DOCTOR> discharged him to the care of his primary physician , Dr. <DOCTOR>Ma</DOCTOR> , in <LOCATION>Taette</LOCATION> .
Dr. <DOCTOR>Ma</DOCTOR> will be working with Dr. <DOCTOR>Besti Kotebreun</DOCTOR> of <HOSPITAL>Ph University Of Medical Center</HOSPITAL> to manage the currently indwelling stents .
MEDICATIONS AT THE TIME OF DISCHARGE :
<DOCTOR>DOATOLI GAMESSHUFF</DOCTOR> , M.D.
DICTATING FOR :
DD :
<DATE>04/08/95</DATE>
CC :
</TEXT>
</RECORD>