<RECORD ID="110">
<TEXT>
<ID>183285857</ID> <HOSPITAL>EH</HOSPITAL>
<ID>79370808</ID>
<ID>451981</ID>
<DATE>12/22/1998</DATE> 12:00:00 AM
PREGNANCY , PREMATURE LABOR 30 WEEKS
Signed
DIS
Admission Date :
<DATE>12/22/1998</DATE>
Report Status :
Signed
Discharge Date :
<DATE>12/29/1998</DATE>
PRINCIPAL DIAGNOSIS :
30 WEEKS GESTATION , PREMATURE LABOR
DISCHARGE DIAGNOSIS :
30 WEEKS GESTATION , PREMATURE LABOR STATUS POST CESAREAN SECTION
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
The patient is a 31 year old gravida-2 para-0 with a known twin gestation with an estimated date of confinement of <DATE>02/27/98</DATE> .
On the day of admission , the patient had an ultrasound which showed the infants to be in the breech /vertex presentation .
Also noted on ultrasound was a shortened cervix at 1.8 centimeters and funneling of the lower uterine segment .
The patient was admitted to the triage area of labor and delivery and noted to be having contractions every two minutes .
She was given one dose of terbutaline with a subsequent tachycardia to 120 .
She was then started on magnesium sulfate with a 4 gram bolus followed by two grams per hour .
This seemed to decrease the frequency of her contractions significantly and she was only having a rare contraction .
Her cervix on admission was closed and about 80 percent effaced .
She was given betamethasone and transferred to the antenatal unit .
She did well for the first two days with only minor complaints of irregular contractions .
On the morning of <DATE>12/24/98</DATE> she seemed to be having more contractions and pelvic exam revealed the cervix to be one centimeter , 80 percent effaced .
Consultation was obtained with Dr. <DOCTOR>Lou</DOCTOR> who suggested at least briefly increasing the infusion rate to see if her pregnancy could be prolonged longer .
She seemed to respond to this with only irregular contractions .
On the evening of <DATE>12/24/98</DATE> , the patient once again complained of increasing contraction frequency as well as back pain .
Examination revealed the cervix to now be 2-3 centimeters dilated and the decision was made to discontinue the magnesium and to perform delivery .
She had a primary Cesarean section because of the breech presentation and on <DATE>Christmas</DATE> she underwent uncomplicated primary Monroe Kerr Cesarean section under spinal anesthesia .
At 2:10 a.m. on <DATE>12/25/98</DATE> the patient was delivered of a 3 pound 5 ounce male infant with Apgars of 7 at one and 8 at five minutes .
At 2:12 a.m. on <DATE>12/25/98</DATE> she was delivered of a male infant weighing 3 pounds and 3 ounces in the vertex position with Apgars of 7 at one and 7 at five minutes .
Both infants were transferred to the Neonatal intensive care unit and were doing well at the time of the maternal discharge .
She did well postoperatively with minimal discomfort .
On the morning of discharge , the patient complained of a warm swollen area on the posterior aspect of her left knee .
Consultation was obtained with the cardiovascular group and the decision was that she had superficial phlebitis of her left leg which could be treated conservatively and would not require Heparin .
The patient was discharged on <DATE>12/29/98</DATE> and is to be seen in the office in two weeks .
She was discharged with prescriptions for Motrin and Tylenol and Peri-Colace as needed .
She is to attemp elevation , heatetc to her left leg understanding that she will be coming to see her infants in the NICU .
Dictated By :
<DOCTOR>ILUA T. DOSE</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>AI7</ID>
Attending :
<DOCTOR>ILUA T. DOSE</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>GP8 MU570/2389</ID>
Batch :
<ID>47491</ID>
Index No. <ID>R8YYSNDZ5</ID>
D :
<DATE>12/31/98</DATE>
T :
<DATE>12/31/98</DATE>
[ report_end ]
</TEXT>
</RECORD>