<RECORD ID="248">
<TEXT>
<ID>921830245</ID> <HOSPITAL>YC</HOSPITAL>
<ID>98403472</ID>
<ID>9622703</ID>
<DATE>8/12/2002</DATE> 12:00:00 AM
SINUSITIS
Signed
DIS
Admission Date :
<DATE>08/12/2002</DATE>
Report Status :
Signed
Discharge Date :
<DATE>08/20/2002</DATE>
ATTENDING :
<DOCTOR>CRILI THONTA TLANDBINDE</DOCTOR> MD
PRINCIPAL DIAGNOSIS :
Miller-Fisher variant Guillain Barre syndrome .
Sixth nerve palsy .
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
The patient is a 45-year-old male who complained of a 2-day history of horizontal diplopia that began in rightward gaze and was now present bilaterally .
Of note , the patient reports a 2-week history of upper respiratory infection and sinus congestion .
He reports that the day before admission , he awoke with diplopia that did resolve with monocular vision .
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION :
The patient had pupils that were equal , round , and reactive to light bilaterally .
Accommodation was intact .
Visual fields were full by confrontation .
Of note , there was right than greater than left abducens weakness noted by the physical examiner on admission .
His strength in his extremities was normal and he had normal reflexes .
MRI of the brain demonstrated significant right sphenoid maxillary and ethmoid sinus inflammation .
HOSPITAL COURSE :
Procedures :
The patient was evaluated initially by the Otolaryngology Service with the consideration that his right-sided sinus disease was contributing to his sixth nerve palsy .
He was started on antibiotic treatment for his sinus findings .
However , further review by Neurology Consult Service indicated that the sinus disease was likely not sufficient to explain the patient &apos;s cranial nerve findings .
The working diagnosis at that point was the Miller-Fisher variant of Guillain-Barre syndrome versus less likely causes .
The patient underwent lumbar puncture and also had an electromyelogram performed .
EMG findings were in fact consistent with variant Guillain-Barre syndrome .
It was then determined that the patient should be started on intravenous immunoglobulin .
He was therefore started with a treatment course of 6 days of IV IgA after obtaining an IgA level .
The patient tolerated this treatment course well .
His cranial neuropathy was monitored carefully and was found to be stable to slightly improving in the first several days of treatment .
He was also treated with IV steroids .
By <DATE>08/20/2003</DATE> , the patient has tolerated the full treatment course and had a substantial improvement in his diplopia .
It was then determined that the patient was safe to discharge .
DISCHARGE MEDICATIONS :
1. Tylenol 650 mg p.o. q. 4-6 hours p.r.n. pain .
2. Hydrochlorothiazide 25 mg p.o. q.d.
3. Lopressor 25 mg p.o. b.i.d.
FOLLOW UP :
The plan for follow up was with Dr. <DOCTOR>Viennee Breutzfreierm</DOCTOR> within 14 days of discharge .
eScription document :
<ID>7-4035513 YUCjzv</ID> Tel
Dictated By :
<DOCTOR>OBEILL , CAOB</DOCTOR>
Attending :
<DOCTOR>TLANDBINDE , CRILI THONTA</DOCTOR> Dictation ID <ID>0369751</ID>
D :
<DATE>10/09/03</DATE>
T :
<DATE>10/09/03</DATE>
[ report_end ]
</TEXT>
</RECORD>