<RECORD ID="337">
<TEXT>
<ID>202030902</ID> <HOSPITAL>SC</HOSPITAL>
<ID>10800403</ID>
<ID>879694</ID>
<DATE>4/29/2000</DATE> 12:00:00 AM
UNSTABLE ANGINA
Signed
DIS
Admission Date :
<DATE>04/29/2000</DATE>
Report Status :
Signed
Discharge Date :
<DATE>05/04/2000</DATE>
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
Ms. <PATIENT>Nuscsmantpiern</PATIENT> is a 59-year-old female with a history of acceleration coronary artery disease over the past month and a positive exercise tolerance test with almost daily angina and substernal chest pressure which was relieved with rest and brought on by minimal exercise .
The patient had an exercise tolerance test on <DATE>04/12/00</DATE> where she exercised for 4 minutes and 16 seconds , developed chest pressure with a nondiagnostic ST changes .
The patient underwent cardiac catheterization which revealed the following :
Left main coronary artery with an ostial 60% stenosis on a left dominant system and no other obstructive lesions in the nondominant right coronary artery system .
The patient is also noted to have atherosclerosis and is status post a left carotid endarterectomy for 85% stenosis in <DATE>01/98</DATE> .
Carotid studies were repeated in <DATE>07/99</DATE> which revealed only mild plaque with a 50% right external carotid stenosis , no stenoses in the internal carotids .
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY :
Hypertension , hyperlipidemia , menopause , on estrogen Progesterone .
PAST SURGICAL HISTORY :
Status post left carotid endarterectomy in <DATE>01/98</DATE> .
ALLERGIES :
No known drug allergies .
MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION :
Imdur 30 mg once a day ; Ecotrin 325 mg once a day ; atenolol 25 mg once a day ; Lipitor 10 mg once a day ; Verapamil 180 mg twice a day ; Premarin ; Provera .
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION :
Non-contributory .
HOSPITAL COURSE :
Ms. <PATIENT>Nuscsmantpiern</PATIENT> was brought to the operating room on <DATE>04/30/00</DATE> where she underwent a coronary artery bypass graft x 2 with left internal mammary artery to the left anterior descending artery and a saphenous vein graft to the obtuse marginal artery .
The patient did well intraoperatively , came off bypass without incident , was brought up to the intensive care unit in normal sinus rhythm and in stable condition .
Postoperatively Ms. <PATIENT>Nuscsmantpiern</PATIENT> did remarkably well .
She was extubated on postoperative day #1 and transferred to the step down unit .
She otherwise had an unremarkable postoperative course and was discharged to home on postoperative day #4 with visiting nurse .
DISCHARGE LABS :
<DATE>05/04/00</DATE> :
Glucose 125 , BUN 17 , creatinine 0.7 , sodium 140 , potassium 4.4 , chloride 100 , CO2 38 , magnesium 1.9 , WBC 9.59 , hemoglobin 9.8 , hematocrit 29.7 , platelets 244 , PT 11.4 , PT / INR 0.9 .
DISCHARGE MEDICATIONS :
Enteric coated aspirin 325 mg once a day ; Colace 100 mg three times a day ; Lopressor 25 mg three times a day ; Niferex 150 mg twice a day ; Percocet 1-2 tabs every 4h p.r.n. pain ; Zantac 150 mg twice a day ; Premarin Provera 0.625/2.5 mg once a day ; Lipitor 10 mg once a day .
DISPOSITION :
Ms. <PATIENT>Nuscsmantpiern</PATIENT> will be discharged to home in stable condition with visiting nurse .
FOLLOWUP :
She will follow up with Dr. <DOCTOR>In Leick</DOCTOR> in six weeks and her cardiologist within the week .
Dictated By :
<DOCTOR>HARLLU JESCBEATHE</DOCTOR> , P.A.
Attending :
<DOCTOR>IN V. LEICK</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>FC55 EB066/8088</ID>
Batch :
<ID>16101</ID>
Index No. <ID>WCXO6ZC9E3</ID>
D :
<DATE>05/04/00</DATE>
T :
<DATE>05/06/00</DATE>
[ report_end ]
</TEXT>
</RECORD>