<RECORD ID="831">
<TEXT>
<ID>672441494</ID>
<HOSPITAL>CTMC</HOSPITAL>
<ID>95090749</ID>
<ID>384704</ID>
<DATE>1/24/1991</DATE> 12:00:00 AM
Discharge Summary
Unsigned
DIS
Admission Date :
<DATE>01/24/1991</DATE>
Report Status :
Unsigned
Discharge Date :
<DATE>02/03/1991</DATE>
CHIEF COMPLAINT :
Aortic stenosis .
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
This is a 68-year-old white male with a long history of aortic stenosis .
He also was status post a cadaveric renal transplant three years ago for chronic renal failure of unknown etiology .
He had dyspnea on exertion increasing for several years .
An echo revealed a peak gradient of 62 with a mean of 39 .
He had normal left ventricular function .
He had an area estimated to be 0.9 cm squared in the aortic valve .
Catheterization showed an ejection fraction of 52% with normal coronaries and excellent output .
He had been on diuretic therapy for the past several months with worsening shortness of breath .
He also had PND , orthopnea and ankle swelling with inability to lie flat .
He had some dizziness with minimal activity .
PAST HISTORY :
Renal failure , status post cadaveric renal transplant ; aortic stenosis ; right eye glaucoma ; hypertension ; Meniere &apos;s disease ; history of peritonitis ; ureteral stent ; colostomy ; cataract surgery .
MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION :
Coumadin 2 mg p.o. daily ; prednisone 10 mg p.o. q.o.d. alternating with 7.5 mg q.o.d. ; Imuran 100 mg daily ; cyclosporine 70 mg p.o. b.i.d. ; Lopressor 25 mg p.o. b.i.d. ; Ventolin two puffs q6h p.r.n.
HOSPITAL COURSE :
The patient was taken to surgery on <DATE>1/25/91</DATE> , where he underwent a #21 St. Jude aortic valve replacement without complications .
He did well during the first few postoperative days , however , he then developed acute renal insufficiency in his grafted kidney .
His creatinine elevated to 3.8 .
He was seen in consult by the renal transplant team and was felt to be prerenal due to hypertensive episodes perioperatively .
He was placed on dopamine and given fluids for diuresis .
His creatinine was brought down to acceptable levels prior to discharge .
His cyclosporine levels were therapeutic but reduced in dosage .
He had some shortness of breath for which he received a left lobe pleurocentesis which was effective in reducing his symptoms .
DISPOSITION :
He was discharged back to his home in <LOCATION>Utah</LOCATION> .
FOLLOW UP will be with his cardiologist for maintenance of his Coumadin levels and his immunosuppressives .
<ID>AY268/3325</ID> <DOCTOR>TOMEDANKELL D. FLOWAYLES , JR</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>CD0</ID>
D :
<DATE>02/04/91</DATE>
Batch :
<ID>7988</ID>
Report :
<ID>I4911C41</ID>
T :
<DATE>02/07/91</DATE>
Dicatated By :
<DOCTOR>REG V. CRANKA</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>OF22</ID>
[ report_end ]
</TEXT>
</RECORD>