<RECORD ID="781">
<TEXT>
<ID>669952543</ID>
<HOSPITAL>CTMC</HOSPITAL>
<ID>329475</ID>
<DATE>2/8/1990</DATE> 12:00:00 AM
Discharge Summary
Unsigned
DIS
Admission Date :
<DATE>02/08/1990</DATE>
Unsigned
Discharge Date :
<DATE>02/13/1990</DATE>
ADMISSION DIAGNOSIS :
VULVAR CANCER .
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
The patient is a 43-year-old gravida II para II white female referred by Dr. <DOCTOR>Ca Shuff</DOCTOR> for evaluation .
She was in her usual state of good health until <DATE>December</DATE> when she was seen emergently for treatment of a perforated colon cancer .
That area was resected with no evidence of metastatic disease .
She has had subsequent CEA&apos;s and scans which were negative .
A tumor was noted on her vulva which was biopsied and revealed squamous cell carcinoma in situ .
ALLERGIES :
NO KNOWN DRUG ALLERGIES .
MEDICATIONS :
None .
PAST SURGICAL HISTORY :
As above with colostomy .
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION :
On admission included HEENT exam which was normal .
Chest was clear .
Heart revealed a regular rate and rhythm .
Abdomen was soft and nontender .
Vulva and right labia replaced by reddish lesion , somewhat raised in the center extending from adjacent to the cuterus to the posterior forchette .
Otherwise , her pelvic exam was negative .
IMPRESSION :
STAGE II SQUAMOUS CELL CARCINOMA OF THE VULVA .
HOSPITAL COURSE :
The plan was for right radical vulvectomy .
1. Vulvectomy :
Her postoperative course was unremarkble .
She was kept on bedrest for two days and then was ambulating and voiding well without trouble on postoperative day number three when the Foley catheter was discontinued .
She has been doing Betadine paint and blow drying the area several times a day and after each bowel movement and urine without incident .
DISPOSITION :
The discharge is to home .
The patient will follow-up with Dr. <DOCTOR>Friednantflirt</DOCTOR> .
She will have <HOSPITAL>AH</HOSPITAL> for support .
________________________________ <ID>YT844/9769</ID> <DOCTOR>LAKO SCARVTWI</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>TH0</ID>
D :
<DATE>02/12/90</DATE>
Batch :
<ID>7753</ID>
Report :
<ID>Y6201H2</ID>
T :
<DATE>02/13/90</DATE>
Dicatated By :
<DOCTOR>RORIEZAILA KOTEKAYSKOTEKAYSCOA</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>SE85</ID>
[ report_end ]
</TEXT>
</RECORD>