<RECORD ID="104">
<TEXT>
<ID>023936379</ID> <HOSPITAL>DH</HOSPITAL>
<ID>9507607</ID>
<ID>213739</ID>
<ID>086306</ID>
<DATE>4/16/2002</DATE> 12:00:00 AM
Discharge Summary
Signed
DIS
Report Status :
Signed
DISCHARGE SUMMARY
NAME :
<PATIENT>BOORMSKI , NIKEE R</PATIENT>
UNIT NUMBER :
<ID>405-53-29</ID>
ADMISSION DATE :
<DATE>04/16/2002</DATE>
DISCHARGE DATE :
<DATE>04/17/2002</DATE>
PRINCIPAL DIAGNOSIS :
Idiopathic cardiomyopathy , history of syncope and non-sustained ventricular tachycardia .
PRINCIPAL PROCEDURE :
Automatic internal cardiac defibrillator generator replacement .
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
Mr. <PATIENT>Boormski</PATIENT> is a 66-year-old gentleman who was admitted for elective generator replacement due to prolonged charge times .
His problem list includes Ventritex Contour Model ICD with prolonged charge time ; 2 ) idiopathic cardiomyopathy ; 3 ) history of syncope ; 4 ) non-sustained ventricular tachycardia ; 5 ) renal insufficiency ; 6 ) chronic hypertension ; 7 ) gallstone pancreatitis ; 8 ) bladder outlet obstruction ; 9 ) history of congestive heart failure .
The patient was seen in the Electrophysiology Clinic as a part of his routine work up .
The ICD which was initially implanted <DATE>March 26 , 1997</DATE> is a Ventritex Contour Model V145AC defibrillator which now needs to be replaced due to excessively long charge times of greater than 30 seconds .
The patient had his device implanted due to idiopathic cardiomyopathy with a low ejection fraction and documented episodes of non-sustained ventricular tachycardia and his most recent echocardiogram on <DATE>10/30/01</DATE> revealed an ejection fraction of 37 percent , diffusely hypokinetic left ventricle .
MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION :
Zestril 20 mg .
PO q.d. Digoxin 0.25 mg .
PO q.d. Lasix 20 mg .
PO q.d. Coumadin alternating with 5 and 2.5 mg .
PO q.o.d. Coreg 25 mg .
PO b.i.d. Tricor 54 mg .
PO b.i.d.
ALLERGIES :
Penicillin .
IMPRESSION :
The final impression is Mr. <PATIENT>Nikee Boormski</PATIENT> was admitted for elective generator replacement due to prolonged charge times .
HOSPITAL COURSE AND TREATMENT :
He had a new Ventritex Contour VVI Model put in on <DATE>April 16 , 2002</DATE> .
His VVI pacemaker function has been set at 40 .
His fibrillation detection criteria were set at 310 milliseconds at a rte of 194 beats per minute .
The tachy arrhythmia therapies for his fibrillation includes a first shock of 600 volts , second shock of 750 volts and a third shock of 750 volts which will be repeated four times .
He has been advised to follow up in three months for an implanted cardiac defibrillator check .
Post procedure Mr. <PATIENT>Boormski</PATIENT> was kept in Hospital overnight .
His implanted cardiac defibrillator evaluation looks fine and his implantation site looks healthy .
He has been given detailed post discharge instructions .
He will follow up in the <HOSPITAL>Penryards Medical Center</HOSPITAL> in about three month &apos;s time with <DOCTOR>Ca Laxtwierst</DOCTOR> .
MEDICATIONS ON DISCHARGE :
Unchanged .
<DOCTOR>MAA ALB</DOCTOR> , M.D.
DICTATING FOR :
Electronically Signed <DOCTOR>ERIN TISIAKI KENGEKOTE</DOCTOR> , M.D. <DATE>04/26/2002</DATE> 18:09
_____________________________ <DOCTOR>ERIN TISIAKI KENGEKOTE</DOCTOR> , M.D.
TR :
<DOCTOR>uuo</DOCTOR>
DD :
<DATE>04/17/2002</DATE>
TD :
<DATE>04/17/2002</DATE> 2:16 P <ID>213739</ID>
cc :
<DOCTOR>ERIN TISIAKI KENGEKOTE</DOCTOR> , M.D. <DOCTOR>MAA ALB</DOCTOR> , M.D.
[ report_end ]
</TEXT>
</RECORD>