<RECORD ID="267">
<TEXT>
<ID>247716377</ID> <HOSPITAL>SC</HOSPITAL>
<ID>89137357</ID>
<ID>823614</ID>
<DATE>5/6/1995</DATE> 12:00:00 AM
Discharge Summary
Signed
DIS
Admission Date :
<DATE>05/06/1995</DATE>
Report Status :
Signed
Discharge Date :
<DATE>05/10/1995</DATE>
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
Patient is a 43 year old white female who had a history twelve years ago of a ventral hernia that was repaired .
In the twelve years prior to this admission , the patient had noted the progressive recurrence of this ventral hernia with progressive enlargement and over the last year , the hernia had been causing her an increasing amount of pain .
The patient presented on <DATE>May 6</DATE> for ventral hernia repair .
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY :
Significant for the ventral hernia as above .
PAST SURGICAL HISTORY :
Significant for ventral hernia repair .
ALLERGIES :
She had no known drug allergies .
CURRENT MEDICATIONS :
On admission were none .
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION :
On admission was remarkable for a moderately obese middle-aged female notable for a large ventral hernia .
HOSPITAL COURSE :
The patient was admitted after her surgery .
The surgery went very well with no complications , however , the hernia was rather large requiring an extensive amount of mesh .
The patient was admitted to make sure she did not have any post-operative ileus .
The patient remained NPO on post-operative day number one and post-operative day number two , was started on clear liquids .
She developed a low grade temperature which resolved spontaneously and on post-operative day number three , was tolerating a regular diet well .
Patient was passing gas with no abdominal discomfort and she had been afebrile for 24 hours .
The patient is to be discharged with follow-up in the <HOSPITAL>Wardca Presiew Hospital</HOSPITAL> on <DATE>May 15 , 1995</DATE> .
DISPOSITION :
DISCHARGE MEDICATIONS :
Tylenol p.r.n.
Dictated By :
<DOCTOR>PADA CELKREARDRAFF</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>SS78</ID>
Attending :
<DOCTOR>DENA D. GAETZFREIERM</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>YY10 CQ724/1198</ID>
Batch :
<ID>5211</ID>
Index No. <ID>NQSJYD2YV6</ID>
D :
<DATE>05/10/95</DATE>
T :
<DATE>05/14/95</DATE>
[ report_end ]
</TEXT>
</RECORD>