<RECORD ID="669">
<TEXT>
<ID>95199917</ID>
DIS
Admission Date :
<DATE>02/11/1990</DATE>
Discharge Date :
<DATE>02/24/1990</DATE>
CHIEF COMPLAINT :
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
He did not have any arrest .
Two days prior to admission , he was seen by his local M.D. for the above symptoms .
Nine days prior to admission , a CT and biopsy showed a large cell cancer .
He had shortness of breath .
He had nausea and diaphoresis .
He went to <HOSPITAL>Ryosentlourdes Hospital</HOSPITAL> , where he ruled in with EKGs and CPKs .
He had a new right bundle and marked ST changes .
PAST HISTORY :
Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease with &quot; marginal PFTs &quot; ; alcohol abuse ; skin graft after a parachute failed to open .
ALLERGIES :
Unclear .
The neck was supple ; carotids were without bruits .
The chest exam revealed crackles .
The cardiac exam revealed tachycardia and very distant sounds .
LABORATORY EXAMINATION :
Potassium 3.3 ; creatinine 1.5 ; hematocrit 38.0 ; white count 65,000 ; platelets 445,000 .
The chest x-ray showed the right upper lung mass .
The patient was admitted to the ICU and was fully monitored with an A-line and Swan .
He was taken to cardiac cath where he was found to have a total occlusion of his LAD after his first diagonal .
His circumflex had a 60% obstruction prior to the obtuse marginal branch with a 60% stenosis of the obtuse marginal branch .
The obtuse marginal second branch was subtotally occluded .
The RCA had an 80% stenosis in its mid portion and 40% distal obstruction .
An intra-aortic balloon pump was placed .
He was then stabilized medically in preparation for surgery .
He did eventually then go to the operating room on <DATE>2/14/90</DATE> , at which time he had an emergency CABG times three with asaphenous vein graft to the obtuse marginal and one onto the PDA .
He was transferred to the CICU postop , where he had his balloon removed after being stabilized .
He was extubated without complications and had his chest tubes removed in a standard fashion .
He then was up ambulating with physical therapy but very slowly , and he was quite weak .
Hematology was asked to consult with the patient .
He was felt to have a leukomoid reaction with his white count postop of around 90,000 .
Oncology and thoracic surgery were consulted .
He will be followed up the week after discharge to see Dr. <DOCTOR>Right</DOCTOR> .
He had a bone scan which showed positive uptake in the right first rib but was otherwise negative .
A head CT was negative .
DISPOSITION :
The patient was discharged home in stable condition with <HOSPITAL>CMC</HOSPITAL> and physical therapy .
MEDICATIONS ON DISCHARGE :
Digoxin 0.25 mg p.o. daily ; Ecotrin one tab p.o. daily ; captopril 12.5 mg p.o. t.i.d. ; Percocet 1-2 tabs p.o. q4-6h p.r.n. pain .
FOLLOW UP will be with Dr. <DOCTOR>Neighroblin</DOCTOR> in 4-6 weeks and by cardiology in two weeks .
Dr. <DOCTOR>Right</DOCTOR> will see him in one week .
1. CARDIOGENIC SHOCK .
2. CORONARY ARTERY DISEASE , STATUS POST AN ANTEROSEPTAL MYOCARDIAL INFARCTION .
INTRA-AORTIC BALLOON PUMP PLACEMENT .
________________________________ <ID>CM335/9278</ID>
<DOCTOR>TOMEDANKELL D. FLOWAYLES , JR</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>FX0</ID>
<DATE>02/23/90</DATE>
<ID>9802</ID>
T :
<DATE>02/28/90</DATE>
<DOCTOR>BIRAY A. KINKEDOUETKOOGLE</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>JB72</ID>
cc :

</TEXT>
</RECORD>