<RECORD ID="684">
<TEXT>
Signed
UNIT NUMBER :
<DATE>03/29/2002</DATE>
<DATE>04/04/2002</DATE> Mr. <PATIENT>Rule</PATIENT> is a 74 year old right handed male who was transferred to the Neurology Service for stroke evaluation .
Mr. <PATIENT>Rule</PATIENT> on <DATE>March 26</DATE> at 1 PM had the acute onset of dizziness , headache , right arm and leg weakness as he was getting to stand up from watching TV .
He went to <HOSPITAL>Ton University Hospital</HOSPITAL> where a head CT was performed that showed no evidence of bleed .
Initial blood pressure on presentation was recorded at 83/47 .
He was treated with aspirin .
MRI was performed that revealed an acute stroke in the left ACA distribution .
MRA revealed question of significant left internal carotid stenosis just proximal to the cavernous portion of the carotid .
For this lesion and question of possible intervention the patient was transferred to <HOSPITAL>Tonwalkma Hospital</HOSPITAL> .
His right upper extremity was found to be 5 - out of 5 .
The patient was ambulating with a walker .
Chronic renal insufficiency on hemodialysis reportedly secondary to NSAID use .
Hypercholesterolemia .
CAD , status post CABG .
BPH .
Anemia .
EF 45% .
Medications on transfer :
Lipitor .
Folic acid .
Phoslo .
Zantac .
Colace .
Subq heparin .
Of note the patient had not been on aspirin prior to his admission at the outside hospital .
SOCIAL HISTORY :
The patient quit tobacco 45 years ago .
His heart was irregularly irregular with a III out of VI systolic murmur at the right upper sternal border .
However several hours later in the morning he was 3 out of 5 of the iliopsoas , quads and hamstrings .
0 out of 5 more distally .
Sensory exam was intact to all modalities in the upper extremities .
He had decreased vibration in the lower extremities bilaterally .
LABORATORY DATA :
HOSPITAL COURSE :
The patient was started on heparin for concern of embolic ACA stroke in the setting of atrial fibrillation or possibly artery to artery embolus given his left carotid stenosis .
He was seen by Interventional NeuroRadiology who recommended a CTA to better visualize question of left ICA stenosis .
However it did show contrast throughout .
It was thought by NeuroRadiology that this lesion given its proximity to the petrous portion in bone would not be amenable to stenting .
Given the embolic appearance of the stroke the patient was changed from heparin to Plavix and aspirin for anticoagulation .
He was not placed on Coumadin given discussion with his primary care doctor and history of multiple GI bleeds on aspirin alone .
He was started on Nexium in addition to Zantac for further GI prophylaxis .
on CTA pt. was noted to have incidental mass of left thyroid gland .
Recommended to have a thyroid fine needle biopsy for further evaluation .
Dr. <DOCTOR>Chiybelb</DOCTOR> will be notified of this finding for follow up .
<DOCTOR>CA SCGACH</DOCTOR> , M.D.
DICTATING FOR :
Electronically Signed
<DOCTOR>CA SCGACH</DOCTOR> , M.D.
<DATE>04/18/2002</DATE> 10:45
_____________________________ <DOCTOR>CA SCGACH</DOCTOR> , M.D.
TR :
<DOCTOR>war</DOCTOR>
DD :
TD :
<DATE>04/03/2002</DATE> 4:22 P <ID>067266</ID>
cc :
<DOCTOR>YUGEORG GINMAV</DOCTOR> , M.D. <DOCTOR>CA SCGACH</DOCTOR> , M.D. STAT

</TEXT>
</RECORD>