<RECORD ID="782">
<TEXT>
<ID>991193550</ID>
<ID>1585733</ID>
<ID>16900/0678</ID>
<ID>362005</ID>
<DATE>11/30/1995</DATE> 12:00:00 AM
DIS
Report Status :
Unsigned
ADMISSION DATE :
<DATE>11-30-95</DATE>
PRINCIPAL DIAGNOSIS :
Gastric ulcer and gastric pericardial fistula , constricting pericarditis , adult respiratory distress syndrome , status post gunshot wounds and paraplegia since 1991 of T4 on down .
He has multiple decubiti on his buttocks and penis .
ALLERGIES :
MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION :
Albuterol inhaler .
Amphotericin B 40 mg. qday .
Ceftazidime 1 gram intravenous q 8 .
Ciprofloxacin 500 mg. po. q12 .
Cisapride 10 mg. po. qid .
Dakin &apos;s solution 1/4 strength to ulcer of penis .
Benadryl 50 mg. intravenous tid prn .
Lasix prn .
Nystatin swish and swallow tid .
Percocet po. q4 to 6 prn .
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
Most recently he was admitted to an outside hospital with a drug overdose in adult respiratory distress syndrome and ultimately found to have Candidal pericarditis which eventually led to constrictive pericarditis .
He had a pericardial window .
He had a barium swallow and endoscopy and was said not to have gastric or pericardial ulcer .
He had been noted to have an ulcer and ultimately when he stabilized it was our feeling that he most likely had a gastric pericardial ulcer and he was transferred here for further management .
We discussed the risks with his family .
It was a very high risk in very poor condition and a cachectic malnourished edematous individuals who have very high venous pressures and shortness of breath .
The family understood that this was a life saving procedure and only carried with it approximately 50% chance of success .
SPECIAL PROCEDURES AND OPERATIONS :
In lieu of a standard discharge summary given this patient &apos;s complicated hospital course and associated illnesses I feel it best to just provide a system summary concerning this patient &apos;s current status .
1. Neurologic and Psychologic :
Otherwise he is awake , alert and appropriate and can respond to questions and can move his upper extremities .
The patient however spends most of his time at bedrest due to decubiti ulcer disease .
2. Cardiac :
He had a cardiac catheterization on <DATE>December 1 , 1995</DATE> that showed no complications , elevated right atrial pressure and moderate pulmonary hypertension .
The cardiac output was five liters per minute with an index at 2.9 liters per minute per meter 2 which is normal .
A full copy of the cardiac catheterization report is enclosed with his transfer materials .
The patient also underwent cardiac ultrasound on <DATE>December 11 , 1995</DATE> that showed abnormal right ventricle wall motion , trace mitral regurgitation , normal left ventricular size and function with an estimated ejection fraction of 64% .
There is Doppler evidence of tricuspid insufficiency and right atrial dilatation .
The right ventricle is dilated and diffusely hypokinetic and there is no evidence of constrictive physiology which was seen on <DATE>December 6 , 1995</DATE> .
A copy of this ultrasound is also found in his records .
The patient is on no specific medications for his cardiac condition .
3. Respiratory :
the patient is status post thoracotomy and has staples and sutures on his chest .
These may be removed when the incisions are noted to be well healed .
The patient is on oxygen by face mask and his saturations have been remaining normal .
His medications for his respiratory system are Albuterol nebulizer 0.5 mg. 2.5 cc. q4hours .
3. GI :
The patient has had gastric ulcer repair and also has a colostomy .
The patient has a sinus tract that was studied with a fistulogram on <DATE>December 25 , 1995</DATE> .
There is no fistula seen .
The patient takes poorly his po. diet .
However he is able to swallow and tolerate po&apos;s .
The patient is able to tolerate po. medicines .
4. GU :
The patient has an ulcer on his penis that has been treated with dressing changes .
It has been noted to be improving .
Until this time he should be kept on three times daily wet to dry dressing changes .
5. Skin :
The patient has multiple decubiti over his body , in particular his perineum and buttocks have large decubiti .
Plastic Surgery was consulted Dr. <DOCTOR>Ca Shuff</DOCTOR> who saw the patient and decided that the patient is not a surgical candidate at this point .
The patient &apos;s activity should be limited to being up in a chair only for several minutes per day and sit on a special pad that the family has purchased .
6. Infectious Disease :
The patient &apos;s white count at the time of discharge is within normal limits .
The patient remains on Fluconazole .
His other antibiotics were discontinued .
His most recent cultures are negative .
The chest X-ray shows no evidence of pneumonia .
The patient has strong narcotic seeking behavior .
The patient for sleep was given Benadryl 25 to 50 mg. qhs. and was not allowed any increases in his narcotics after weaning him down to just requiring the Oxycodone .
A complete summary of the patient &apos;s medications are as follows :
Albuterol nebulizer 0.5 mg. 2.5 cc. q4hours .
Nortriptyline 25 mg. po. qhs .
Saline wet to dry dressing changes three times daily to penis and pelvis decubiti , 40% humidified oxygen , Fluconazole 200 mg. po. bid .
Lasix 2.5 mg. intravenous qid .
Prilosec 20 mg. po. qd .
Benadryl 25 to 50 mg. po. qhs prn .
Physicians that took care of this patient while at the <HOSPITAL>Ph University Of Medical Center</HOSPITAL> are as follows :
Admitting Physician and Thoracic Surgeon :
<DOCTOR>Reg Cranka</DOCTOR> , M.D.
Consulting Urology was <DOCTOR>Ryna Baker</DOCTOR> , M.D.
Consulting Plastic Surgeon :
<DOCTOR>Ca Shuff</DOCTOR> , M.D.
<DOCTOR>Cealme Maressythe</DOCTOR> , M.D.
Infectious Disease Consultant :
Dr. <DOCTOR>Jesc</DOCTOR> .
Psychiatry :
Dr. <DOCTOR>Rencobe</DOCTOR> and Dr. <DOCTOR>Saddbeem</DOCTOR> .
Pain Service :
Dr. <DOCTOR>Shuff</DOCTOR> .
In summary this is a 25 year old male with a very complicated history and a patient of Dr. <DOCTOR>Breunkays</DOCTOR> &apos;s .
The patient was seen at <HOSPITAL>Ph University Of Medical Center</HOSPITAL> for problem regarding his constrictive pericarditis and underwent a surgical procedure to correct this .
The patient also had a gastric ulcer repaired at the same time .
Other issues of the patient are chronic and most likely will be followed up in hospitals closer to the patient &apos;s home .
If there are any questions regarding his care they should be directed to Dr. <DOCTOR>Cranka</DOCTOR> &apos;s office at <HOSPITAL>Ph University Of Medical Center</HOSPITAL> and we will be happy to contact any or all of the consultations concerned with <PATIENT>Hauth</PATIENT> &apos;s care .
DICTATING FOR :
<DOCTOR>REG CRANKA</DOCTOR> , M.D.
TR :
<DOCTOR>fp / bmot</DOCTOR>
DD :
<DATE>12-27-95</DATE>
TD :
<DATE>12/27/95</DATE>
CC :
STAT :
</TEXT>
</RECORD>