<RECORD ID="726">
<TEXT>
<ID>180414134</ID>
<HOSPITAL>PUOMC</HOSPITAL>
<ID>8987576</ID>
<ID>936967</ID>
<DATE>09/08/1996</DATE> 12:00:00 AM
Discharge Summary
Unsigned
DIS
Report Status :
Unsigned
DISCHARGE SUMMARY
NAME :
<PATIENT>PRUESSCHIRD , RIIE</PATIENT>
UNIT NUMBER :
<ID>825-78-07</ID>
<DATE>09/08/96</DATE>
DISCHARGE DATE :
<DATE>09/17/96</DATE>
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
This 82 year old retired engineer has had multiple admissions to the <HOSPITAL>Ph University Of Medical Center</HOSPITAL> for multiple strokes and a spontaneous subdural hematoma and prostatic hypertrophy .
He has been managing at home on restricted activity but able to get around with a walker but on the day before admission he became increasing dyspneic and on the day of admission he collapsed and was unable to walk to his bed .
For this he was admitted .
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION :
His prostate enlarged and he had no peripheral edema .
LABORATORY DATA :
He had mild elevation of the WBC intermittently grossly bloody urine .
No cultures were positive but the chest x-ray showed bilateral densities more on the left than the right compatible with aspiration pneumonia .
There were no radiographic indications of congestive heart failure .
HOSPITAL COURSE AND TREATMENT :
He is transferred to <HOSPITAL>Louline Mauikings Medical Center</HOSPITAL> for future rehabilitation and hopeful return home with considerable support and assistance .
DISCHARGE DIAGNOSIS :
Aspiration pneumonia bilateral , multiple strokes , chronic atrial fibrillation , prostatic hypertrophy with gross hematuria .
MEDICATIONS ON DISCHARGE :
Hytrin 2mg at bedtime .
Ticlid 0.25 g po bid .
Bronchodilators as needed .
DOCTOR &apos;S DISCHARGE ORDERS :
Strict aspiration precautions with avoidance of clear liquids and all other liquids thickened .
Increased ambulation with assistance and daily pulmonary physical therapy .
<DOCTOR>TOOB OBESTIMEUPH</DOCTOR> , M.D.
<DOCTOR>ua</DOCTOR>
DD :
<DATE>09/16/96</DATE> 4:10 P
cc :
<DOCTOR>DOJE EED BOLMSHI</DOCTOR> , M.D. <DOCTOR>TOOB I OBESTIMEUPH</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>l1xk</ID> STAT

</TEXT>
</RECORD>