<RECORD ID="739">
<TEXT>
<ID>125721767</ID>
<HOSPITAL>CTMC</HOSPITAL>
<ID>34028893</ID>
<ID>597337</ID>
<DATE>3/31/2001</DATE> 12:00:00 AM
Discharge Summary
DIS
Admission Date :
Report Status :
Signed
Discharge Date :
MYASTHENIA GRAVIS .
SECONDARY DIAGNOSES :
1. HYPOTHYROIDISM .
2. HISTORY OF THYMOMA , STATUS POST RESECTION .
4. HISTORY OF COLON CANCER , STATUS POST RESECTION .
OPERATIONS AND PROCEDURES :
ECHOCARDIOGRAM , CARDIAC CATHETERIZATION , EMG , CT SCAN OF THE CHEST .
MEDICATIONS :
DIET :
No restrictions .
ACTIVITY :
As tolerated .
HOSPITAL COURSE :
This is a 72-year-old male with a history of thymoma resected in 1996 , chronic obstructive pulmonary disease , hypothyroidism who was transferred from <HOSPITAL>Gobay Hos Memorial Hospital</HOSPITAL> for an myocardial infarction and cardiac catheterization .
The patient developed shortness of breath at home and the EMTs were called and the patient was found to be in respiratory distress .
He was transferred to <HOSPITAL>Gobay Hos Memorial Hospital</HOSPITAL> where chest x-ray showed left lower lobe infiltrate and cardiac enzymes were elevated with a CK of 297 , MB fraction of 38 and troponin of 12 .
The patient was transferred to the medicine service at the <HOSPITAL>Retelk County Medical Center</HOSPITAL> and underwent cardiac catheterization which was negative for disease .
He continued to complain of shortness of breath with an episode of respiratory failure in the hospital requiring 100% nonrebreather .
Neurology was consulted for difficulty lifting his arms .
On consultation the patient admitted to dysphasia and periods of diplopia in the past .
He was started on IV ig and IV Solu-Medrol for a diagnosis of myasthenia gravis given his past history of thymoma .
He markedly improved after a dose of Mestinon .
He completed a five-day course of IV ig .
His work up included acetylcholine esterase , receptor antibodies , thyroglobulin antibody is pending .
An ANA and rheumatoid factor were negative .
Sed rate was 58 and repeat 75 .
Thoracic Surgery was consulted and recommended repeating the CT scan in six weeks as an outpatient .
This could represent either recurrence of scar tissue .
The patient was tapered to p.o. prednisone and tolerated Mestinon 30 mg q. 4h with 180 mg longacting at bedtime .
<DOCTOR>LENNI E. STENT</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>UQ5 MX420/8849</ID>
Batch :
Index No. <ID>EJDFG7458J</ID>
D :
<DATE>04/07/01</DATE>
T :
<DATE>04/10/01</DATE>

</TEXT>
</RECORD>