<RECORD ID="773">
<TEXT>
<HOSPITAL>PUOMC</HOSPITAL>
<ID>2681723</ID>
<ID>64704/9r71</ID>
<DATE>4/6/1995</DATE> 12:00:00 AM
ACUTE MYOCARDIAL INFARCTION .
Unsigned
DIS
Report Status :
Unsigned
<DATE>4/6/95</DATE>
DISCHARGE DATE :
<DATE>4/16/95</DATE>
Acute myocardial infarction .
ASSOCIATED DIAGNOSIS :
status post aortic valve replacement , status post coronary artery bypass grafting .
PRINCIPAL PROCEDURE :
Percutaneous angioplasty of the right coronary artery , <DATE>4/9/95</DATE> .
OTHER PROCEDURES :
directional angioplasty of the right coronary artery , left main and left anterior descending vessels .
DOCTORS DISCHARGE ORDERS :
Lanoxin 0.375 mg. daily .
Coumadin as adjusted by Prothrombin times , Isordil 20 mg. tid , Micronase 1.25 mg. daily , aspirin 81 mg. daily , nitroglycerin 0.3 mg. SL prn .
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
The patient is a seventy two year old man who a number of years ago underwent coronary bypass surgery at another institution .
This took place in 1983 .
In 1992 he underwent redo surgery and aortic valve replacement .
In <DATE>April 1994</DATE> he presented with an acute inferior myocardial infarction and was given Streptokinase .
He had recurrent pain and went to the Catheter Laboratory where a proximal right coronary artery lesion was angioplastied .
A relook several days later led to a repeat percutaneous transluminal coronary angioplasty .
Slightly increased in recent months .
His electrocardiogram showed increased T wave inversions in V3 and V4 and 1 mm .
ST segment depression in V3 through V6 .
His examination was largely benign after he was made pain free .
The pulse was 75 , blood pressure 120/80 , respirations 18 , and he was afebrile .
The chest was clear and the cardiac rhythm was regular .
There were normal prothetic valves .
There was a grade II-II apical and systolic murmur .
The abdomen was negative and there was no edema of the feet .
The electrocardiogram demonstrated normal sinus rhythm with poor R wave progression , left atrial enlargement and T wave inversion in leads V 4 , 5 , and

</TEXT>
</RECORD>