<RECORD ID="804">
<TEXT>
<ID>203669293</ID>
<HOSPITAL>PUOMC</HOSPITAL>
<ID>6344600</ID>
<ID>35955/he64</ID>
<ID>198283</ID>
<DATE>8/18/1995</DATE> 12:00:00 AM
METASTATIC SMALL CELL LUNG CANCER .
Unsigned
DIS
Report Status :
Unsigned
<DATE>8/18/95</DATE>
DISCHARGE DATE :
<DATE>8/24/95</DATE>
PRINCIPAL DIAGNOSIS :
Metastatic Small Cell Lung Cancer .
ASSOCIATED DIAGNOSIS :
Paralyzed Right Hemidiaphragm .
2. History of breast Cancer 1990 .
DOCTORS DISCHARGE ORDERS :
Decadron 4 mg. o tid , Cimetidine 400 mg. po bid , Tegritol 100 mg. po qid , oxygen at 3 liters per minute .
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
Mrs. <PATIENT>Shuff</PATIENT> was transferred to <HOSPITAL>Ph University Of Medical Center</HOSPITAL> because of the development of a sudden marked increase in her level of dyspnea .
She was known to have metastatic small cell lung carcinoma for which she had been treated by Dr. <DOCTOR>Iand Bontbreun</DOCTOR> with multiple courses of chemotherapy as well as localized radiation therapy .
A few days prior to admission she developed severe dyspnea .
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION :
On physical examination she was markedly dyspneic , sitting upright and completely unable to lie flat .
Decreased breath sounds right upper lobe .
No murmur , rub or gallop or cardiomegaly was noted .
One finger hepatomegaly was present without splenomegaly and there was no peripheral edema .
HOSPITAL COURSE :
The patient was admitted to the hospital and seen in consultation by Dr. <DOCTOR>Oarekote</DOCTOR> from the Department of chemotherapy , Dr. <DOCTOR>Skizeis</DOCTOR> from Radiation Therapy , both of whom conclude that they did not have any additional therapy , which would improve her condition .
Essentially this excluded both coring or laser removal of central airway tumor as well as endobronchial brachy therapy .
She was discharged to be cared for at home or possibly in the Hospice at <HOSPITAL>Vaila Medical Center</HOSPITAL> .
<DOCTOR>LENNI BREUTZOLN</DOCTOR> , M.D.
TR :
<DOCTOR>wj / bmot</DOCTOR>
DD :
<DATE>9/14</DATE>/&apos;06
TD :
<DATE>08/25/95</DATE>
CC :
Dr. <DOCTOR>Breutzoln</DOCTOR>
</TEXT>
</RECORD>