<RECORD ID="819">
<TEXT>
<ID>570922581</ID>
<ID>016906</ID>
<DATE>1/11/1996</DATE> 12:00:00 AM
Discharge Summary
Signed
DIS
Admission Date :
<DATE>01/11/1996</DATE>
Report Status :
Signed
Discharge Date :
<DATE>01/19/1996</DATE>
IDENTIFICATION :
Ms. <PATIENT>Less</PATIENT> was initially admitted to the Vascular Surgery Service for Dr. <DOCTOR>Scosthuang</DOCTOR> and was recently transferred to the Neurosurgery Service under the care of Dr. <DOCTOR>Pae</DOCTOR> .
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
Ms. <PATIENT>Less</PATIENT> is a 79 year old white female with history of non small cell lung cancer diagnosed in <DATE>02/95</DATE> .
She presented to the hospital with a numb right leg this morning and underwent an emergent embolectomy .
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY :
Coronary artery disease status post myocardial infarction in 1990 , peptic ulcer disease and hypertension .
MEDICATIONS :
Medications on admission were Coumadin , Digoxin Synthroid , Lopressor and Zantac .
On <DATE>1/18/96</DATE> , she had an acute change in mental status and underwent an emergent head CT scan which showed a massive subarachnoid hemorrhage with bleeding in the subarachnoid space , and throughout the ventricles .
She also had significant hydrocephalus .
Follow up CT scan showed worsening of her hydrocephalus and she had a ventriculostomy placed in the Intensive Care Unit .
She failed to improve following placement of the ventriculostomy and her poor prognosis was discussed with the family .
The family at that point considering the multiple system involvement of her diseases , decided to make the patient DNR and withdraw care .
The patient expired on <DATE>1/19/96</DATE> at 11:35 p.m.
The medical examiner was called and the case was discussed , and he declined autopsy of the case .
Dictated By :
<DOCTOR>RORIEZAILA FERNE KOTEKAYSKOTEKAYSCOA</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>AV9</ID>
Attending :
<DOCTOR>NAREA L. RUDESTHIR</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>XS62 RS286/0162</ID>
Batch :
<ID>2998</ID>
<DATE>01/19/96</DATE>
T :

</TEXT>
</RECORD>