<RECORD ID="211">
<TEXT>
<ID>915325617</ID> <HOSPITAL>YC</HOSPITAL>
<ID>31922172</ID>
<ID>731679</ID>
<DATE>4/23/2001</DATE> 12:00:00 AM
LEFT FEMORAL NECK FRACTURE
Signed
DIS
Admission Date :
<DATE>04/23/2001</DATE>
Report Status :
Signed
Discharge Date :
<DATE>04/28/2001</DATE>
FINAL DIAGNOSIS :
LEFT FEMUR OPEN REDUCTION AND INTERNAL FIXATION .
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS :
The patient is a 53 year old woman who presents to <HOSPITAL>Ymam Center</HOSPITAL> after a mechanical fall onto her left hip while doing laundry .
The patient reports that she twisted and lost her balance causing a fall directly onto her hip .
She did not hit her head .
There was no loss of consciousness .
She currently complains of left hip pain and groin pain without any other complaints .
She has no numbness , tingling , or weakness in her legs .
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY :
Hypertension .
PAST SURGICAL HISTORY :
None .
ALLERGIES :
Nifedipine causes headaches .
MEDICATIONS :
Atenolol 50 mg p.o. q.d. , Zestril 10 mg p.o. q.d. , and aspirin 325 mg p.o. q.d.
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION :
VITAL SIGNS :
She is afebrile .
Her vital signs are stable .
She is alert and oriented .
HEART :
Regular rate and rhythm .
LUNGS :
Clear to auscultation bilaterally .
Pelvis is stable to AP and lateral compression .
EXTREMITIES :
Her bilateral upper extremities are nontender with sensation and motor intact .
Her right lower extremity is nontender with full range of motion .
Her left lower extremity is shortened by 1 cm .
She has swelling and tenderness of her greater trochanter area .
She has sensation to light touch which is intact .
She has bilateral palpable dorsalis pedis pulse and posterior tibial pulse .
Her strength is 5/5 bilaterally .
LABORATORY DATA :
The x-ray is significant for posteriorly displaced and complete subcapital femoral neck fracture .
HOSPITAL COURSE :
The patient was admitted to <HOSPITAL>Ymam Center</HOSPITAL> on <DATE>4/23/01</DATE> .
The patient was preopped for surgical repair of her hip fracture .
On <DATE>4/24/01</DATE> the patient went to the operating room for left hip open reduction and internal fixation which she tolerated well without complications .
Perioperatively she was kept on antibiotics for emperic therapy .
She was started on Coumadin anticoagulation with a goal INR of 1.5 to 2.0 .
She was made touch down weight bearing on her left lower extremity and physical therapy was consulted to assist with activity .
Her diet was advanced as tolerated .
Her IV was hep-locked on postoperative day # 1 .
On the evening of postoperative day # 1 the patient spiked a fever to 102.2 thought secondary to atelectasis .
She had no further temperature spikes throughout her hospital stay .
She tolerated a regular diet , ambulated with physical therapy , and voided without difficulty .
The patient was accepted to a rehabilitation facility and , on postoperative day # 4 , she was discharged from <HOSPITAL>Ymam Center</HOSPITAL> and transferred for further physical therapy in rehabilitation .
DISPOSITION :
The patient is to continue physical therapy with touch down weight bearing as tolerated .
Please apply a dry sterile dressing to her left leg incision q.d.
Titrate her dose of Coumadin for a goal INR of 1.5 to 2.0.
Please call the results of the PT / INR to <PHONE>( 344 ) 661-0162</PHONE> at the Coumadin clinic .
Call <HOSPITAL>Ymam Center</HOSPITAL> if the patient experiences fevers or chills , redness or discharge from her surgical site .
FOLLOWUP :
The patient is to follow-up with Dr. <DOCTOR>Area</DOCTOR> in the orthopedic clinic in two weeks .
DISCHARGE MEDICATIONS :
Tylenol 650 mg p.o. q4h p.r.n. fever or headache , Albuterol nebulizer 2.5 mg nebulizer q4h p.r.n. wheeze , Atenolol 50 mg p.o. q.d. , Colace 100 mg p.o. b.i.d. , Hydrochlorothiazide 25 mg p.o. q.d. , Atrovent inhaler 2 puffs inhaled q.i.d. , Zestril 10 mg p.o. q.d. , Percocet 1 to 2 tablets p.o. q4h p.r.n. pain , Coumadin 3 mg p.o. q.d. - please titrate dose for goal INR of 1.5 to 2.0 and call results to <PHONE>( 344 ) 661-0162</PHONE> .
Dictated By :
<DOCTOR>YERTREY AREA</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>DR58</ID>
Attending :
<DOCTOR>KEMA ORT</DOCTOR> , M.D. <ID>LH6 VT739/0058</ID>
Batch :
<ID>1496</ID>
Index No. <ID>THTCIDC335</ID>
D :
<DATE>04/28/01</DATE>
T :
<DATE>04/28/01</DATE>
[ report_end ]
</TEXT>
</RECORD>